Izabela Pikula Curriculum Vitae

Flat A, Melrose House, Melrose Gardens

London W6 7RW

Tel.: 07975678836
Email: <u>i.j.pikula@gmail.com</u>

Linkedin: https://uk.linkedin.com/in/izabelapikula

GitHub: https://github.com/iza-pik

SoloLearn: https://www.sololearn.com/Profile/10567664

Front-End Developer working with React.js to build responsive applications.

Experienced translator and project manager with good problem-solving skills and an excellent eye for detail. Passionate about learning new skills and tackling new challenges.

Projects

- Personal Portfolio (<u>live demo</u> / <u>repository</u>)
- Weather Widget (<u>live demo</u> / <u>repository</u>)
- Calculator (<u>live demo</u> / <u>repository</u>)
- Flutter App
- Data Visualisation with Highcharts
- Step Counting App (implemented with React Native)
- Technical Documentation
- · Game of Life
- Financial Calculator
- · Product Landing Page

Skills

- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (ES6+)
- React.js
- TypeScript
- Git
- TDD (React Testing Library/Jest)
- APIs (fetching and using data)
- basic SQL/MongoDB
- SASS, styled-components
- Python
- Dart and Flutter
- · Computer-Assisted Translation tools

Work experience

August 2021 – ongoing

Front-End Software Engineer, Edozo, London

March 2019 - July 2021

React Developer, Symposium OÜ, London

Working in a team of React.js developers, in an Agile environment.

Using GitHub to contribute to the code base of the project.

Building and styling components, routing to navigate components throughout the site.

Following design briefs and adding functionality to the application.

Writing unit tests.

April 2019 - July 2021

Project Manager, Life Sciences, RWS Group (former SDL plc), London

Part of Life Sciences team in a global software localisation, translation and content management company. Managing multilingual translation projects, using Studio 2019-2021, TMS, MultiTrans, machine translation etc.

Lead for the majority of the Regulated Industries client accounts.

Working with the engineering team hosting the client's website, ensuring new content is translated and localised at regular cycles.

Training junior team members.

Reporting KPIs, financial data analysis.

Certifications: SDL Trados Studio 2019 New Features, SDL Trados Studio 2019 for Project Managers

August 2013 – March 2019 Production Assistant, Smallworld Translation Services Ltd, London

Pharmaceutical translation, proofreading and project management

August 2013 – March 2019 Freelance Translator and Proofreader

Translation and localisation EN, FR, ES > PL and PL, FR, ES > EN

April-June 2014 Trainee Polish Translator, Polish Translation Unit at the General Secretariat

of the European Parliament in Luxembourg

April-July 2013 Transcreation Project Manager

Creative Culture Ltd, London

Izabela Pikula Curriculum Vitae

Before 2013 Voluntary work:

Part of "TED. Ideas worth spreading" translation team (www.ted.com): subtitling of TED conferences into Polish.

"Top Class in Science" international translation project (localisation of the website for the pilot project of a competition between several European countries, translation of a science olympiad quiz).

Education

| Laucation | |
|------------------------|---|
| 2021 | CS50's Mobile App Development with React Native (Harvard edX) In progress |
| June – July 2021 | Flutter Bootcamp (Google Developer Group) Dart, Flutter, Firebase, Google Cloud Platform. |
| Sept. – Nov. 2019 | GDG Cloud London JavaScript Crash Course (Google Developer Group) JS & ES6, Node.js, Promises & async programming, APIs, Express.js, MongoDB, Testing, Deployment. |
| June 2019 | Responsive Web Design Developer Certification (FreeCodeCamp, 300 hours) HTML, CSS, Applied Visual Design, Accessibility, Responsive Design, Flexbox, Grid. |
| Sept. 2011 – Feb. 2013 | MA with Distinction in Applied Translation Studies, University of East Anglia |
| Sept. 2007 – July 2011 | BA with First Class Honours in Translation, Media with French and Spanish , University of East Anglia |
| Sept. 2009 – June 2010 | ERASMUS student in France and Spain (year-abroad academic research project): |

Languages

Native proficiency:
 Full professional proficiency:
 English
 Spanish
 French
 Elementary proficiency:
 Polish
 Web development talks and events
 Photography, design, visual arts
 Languages and translation tools
 Travel and hiking

· Universidad Antonio de Nebrija, Madrid

Other interests

Université Jean Moulin, Lyon